Luis Rodriguez Castromil

luisrc5@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/luisrc/ | London, UK

PROFILE

Solving business problems via Technology for the last 10+ years. Solutions to complex problems must be simple, which is usually challenging to implement.

During my career as Engineer I've started in Software working on all phases of SDLC to become a Lead and move towards Platforms, Cloud and DevOps.

I've worked with AWS/Cloud, Terraform, GitLab CI/CD Pipelines, Architecture, Serverless, Microservices, Jenkins, VMWare, Containers, Ansible, Scripting, PHP/JS/Python, CI/CD design/implementation, Deployment strategies, Testing, Migrations, Artefact/Package Management, Linux Admin, Databases Relational and NoSQL, Reverse Proxy, Redis. I've worked as Senior DevOps, Tech Lead, Release Lead, Dev Lead always with a focus on Team and Culture building and transformation.

CAREER

Capgemini - London, UK

2017 - Present

Senior Platform/DevOps Engineer - 2021-Present

Built a greenfield Platform based on a **Serverless Microservices Architecture**, part of their National Critical Infrastructure for the biggest public service department in the UK, able to handle more than 200 transactions per second, configured to scale automatically for future growth and spikes in traffic during busy times of the day/week.

The Serverless Infrastructure (AWS) contains APIGWs, Lambdas and SQS as main components as well as NoSQL and Relational Databases and EC2 instances for the Front-End applications. Automation via pipelines with GitLab CI/CD to build and deploy into AWS our Terraform managed Infrastructure as Code and NodeJS functions/application code. Responsible for the release of the Microservices into Production, part of the On-Call rotation for Live Support.

As Senior DevOps I built a cross-project DevOps Team of ~10 Engineers which supports several platforms, setting the Vision, Strategies and Principles with the DevOps Lead.

Senior Software Engineer - 2018-2021

As **Tech Lead** of the Platform I acted as SME for Drupal/Web tier, participated in Architecture and decisions forums and mentored and upskilled team members. Part of a "System Architect/Engineering" team in a SAFe-like environment, providing support for other teams and the platform in general. Responsible for the migration, improvements and consolidation of Drupal 6-7 sites into one **Drupal 8**.

As **Release Lead** I was the main responsible for a public facing Platform Releases of a high profile FTSE100 client. During this time and following Continuous Improvements I've improved release time from a 4 week cadence to scheduled releases every week and having an option to ad-hoc releases within the same day.

As **Platform/DevOps Engineer** I worked on a **Jenkins 2** migration, built the local dev environment and deployment process for **Drupal 8** and reduced the Release cadence from 4 weeks to once a week in a complex environment. I got experience working with multi-tier platform tools/systems like **Reverse Proxy** (Zeus), Caching layer (Memcached and **Redis**),

Infrastructure as Code (**Terraform**), Configuration as Code (Puppet and **Ansible**), or scripting languages (**Bash**, **Python** and Capistrano) as well as **Automated Testing** (Unit, Integration and Volume) or CI/CD (**Jenkins**) with GitOps automated triggers.

Lead Software Engineer - 2017

As a **Software Engineer** I led multiple dev teams in different phases with applications based on **Drupal**, **AngularJS** and **Rest API** integration.

iterate. - Dublin, Ireland

2012 - 2017

Senior Software Engineer - 2015-2017

The company kept growing and I took more responsibilities as Senior Developer, leading a team of 5 Developers between backend and frontend and being responsible for the delivery of all the software solutions. I was also responsible for the local development setup for the team as well as the delivery and deployment into Production of the Drupal sites using a Platform as a Service solution. I worked on several high profile clients including FTSE100 and EuroStoxx50 companies. I worked on a big Emergency Platform migration for most of our hosted Production sites that took place in less than 48 hours.

Software Engineer - 2013-2015

Following the growth of the company I became the Lead Developer and led the development of all the new and existing clients while the founder moved to a Managing role, working on all phases of the SDLC, from working in new bids to acquire new clients, building and deploying the sites and then supporting the Live incidents and Customer Support for clients.

Junior Developer - 2012-2013

I was responsible for the development of the Drupal sites and features for a variety of clients, from Public sector to Private sector clients.

TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS

2022 | Azure Data Fundamentals - GCP Cloud Digital Leader - Connected Manager

2021 | HashiCorp Terraform Associate

2020 | AWS Solutions Architect Associate - Azure Fundamentals - Architect LvI 0

2019 | AWS Cloud Practitioner

2010-2012 | Network Computer Systems Administration.

2008-2010 | Telecommunications and Computer Systems.











LANGUAGES

- **English**: Professional.

Spanish / Galician: Native.

References available on request.